# Nilpa K. Jhaveri

#### Education

#### MIT CSAIL xPro Certificate

Human Computer Interaction Computer Science & Al Lab May - June 2020

UX intensive program BloomTech (Lambda) Full-time 8-mo. UX curriculum July 2019 - March 2020

#### **Bachelor of Architecture**

College of Architecture & Environmental Design
Cal Poly, San Luis Obispo

CSU International Programs Architecture & Italian Full academic year Florence, Italy

#### Credentials

LEED Accredited Professional Licensed Architect, Colorado

#### Skills

UX / UI / Interaction design
Foundational UX research
UX strategy
Information architecture Systems
thinking
Flow diagramming
Wireframing & mockups
Prototyping & transitions
Presentation
Accessibility
Usability testing
Engineer hand-off
Project management
Client interface

## Product UX/UI Designer | Architect

nilpa.j@gmail.com • portfolio: jhaverini.github.io • linkedin.com/in/njhaveri

#### **Experience**

#### Product Designer (UX/UI) - Consulting

SAN FRANCISCO & SAN CARLOS, CA | SEP. 2019 - PRESENT

- Iterant: Strategized on early design for a three-sided circular economy marketplace providing incentives for enterprise-scale B2B reuse of goods in supply chains. Conducted foundational research & validation, laid out information architecture, advised on MVP site, mocked & prototyped critical screens for pitch decks.
- Vox Pulmini: Created user flows, mockups, and UI prototypes for mobile app for participants to volunteer audio samples in support of affordable AI-based home healthcare management for children. Emphasized simplicity and intuitive ease-of-use.
- **Key Conservation:** Streamlined a lengthy onboarding flow for a mobile app enabling local biodiversity support through citizen science. Cocreated mockups, prototypes, and UI guidelines for app redesign. Proposed tests for validation and phased roll-out of features.
- HamiltonPay: Designed high-fidelity, mobile-first, responsive web app screens (marketing & platform) for B2C product demos for a payment tool serving small businesses, using smart contracts and intuitive, minimal form field entries. Adapted a design system based on Tailwind UI. Crafted prototypes to communicate transitions with team. Sole designer working cross-functionally as part of the founding team.
- **SpeakOut:** Simplified the overall website information architecture and content for a Bahraini English language school serving low-income students, to increase usability. Added mobile-first, responsive, simple registration flows to help resolve attendance and payment shortfalls.

#### Senior Project Architect / Project Manager - NELSON Worldwide

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2014 - 2019 (FKA WK DESIGN GROUP)

From definition to functional use, designed and led workplace experience projects, specializing in startups and game design studios. Responsible for project management and client/consultant relations. Point-person for QA on all out-going work office-wide, from regulatory approvals to engineer hand-off, focusing on implementation (buildability), fire/safety compliance, accessibility, completeness, and consistency with design systems. Mentored junior staff.

#### **Project Architect** - HGA Architects & Engineers

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2008 - 2014

Conducted stakeholder interviews and met with user groups in sketch sessions to improve on workflows in healthcare environments. Translated feedback into

# Nilpa K. Jhaveri

### Tools

Figma / Sketch
Photoshop / Affinity Photo
Illustrator & InDesign
HTML & CSS
Familiar with VS Code
Familiar with Github
Miro / Lucidchart / Visio
SketchUp / 3D Studio VIZ
AutoCAD & Revit

#### Mentions

- Neonatal ICU, Kaiser San Diego<sup>2</sup> covered in "Tiny Miracle Baby Finally Big Enough to Go Home," CBS News 8 San Diego.
- Diamond Heights Residence<sup>1</sup> mentioned in <u>House Colors</u>, by Susan Hershman.
- Glen Park Remodel<sup>1</sup>
  mentioned in <u>Big Ideas for</u>
  <u>Small Spaces</u>, by Sunset
  Books.
- American Institute of Architects "Small Firms Great Projects" Exhibits: Sea Ranch Residence & Studio<sup>1</sup> and Noe Valley Residence<sup>1</sup>.

- 1 Designer, Veverka Architects
- 2 Proj. Designer, HGA Architects & Engineers

# **Product UX/UI Designer** | Architect

nilpa.j@gmail.com · portfolio: jhaverini.github.io · linkedin.com/in/njhaveri

## Experience (continued)

designs for iteration, prototyping, and implementation. Helped stakeholders visualize and prioritize planning, scoping, and feasibility of future improvements for projects ranging from clinics to city blocks. Managed office-wide staffing projections, working with other corporate office locations to balance staffing needs. Sustainability Council member for SF office.

### Architectural Designer - Consultant - 2007-2008

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2008 - 2014

Collaborated on laboratory, manufacturing, corporate office, and custom single-family home projects with multiple design firms.

#### Associate Designer - Veverka Architects

SAN FRANCISCO, CA | 2000 - 2007

Identified & advocated for unique needs of end-users of single family homes, multi-unit condos, and small commercial spaces, from concept to execution to functional use. Crafted custom spaces and communicated technical & design specifications across disciplines, under apprenticeship to the principal architect. Arranged office learning sessions and started a green materials library for sharing insights on environmentally-friendly building materials.

#### Junior Designer - Anderson Brule Architects

SAN JOSE, CA | 1999 - 2000

Co-conducted end-user research, focus groups, visioning sessions, and community workshops for foundational groundwork for civic projects. Audited existing conditions and workflows, and identified end-user and stakeholder goals. Analyzed findings and created visual representations on which to base design solutions.

#### About Me

Practicing human-centered design for 10+ years for physical and digital interactions, with an emphasis on sustainability and social good. Serial half marathoner (will run for donuts). Healthcare system hacker, penetrating the bureaucracy. Lifelong learner with a passion for physical media: wood, glass, ceramics.